André ANJOS

Doctor of Sciences on Electronics Engineering

CERN, Genève 23 CH-1211 - Suisse/Switzerland

Work phone: +4122767583

Birth: December, 31st. 1973 (currently 35)

Marital Status: Married

Nationality: Brazilian, from Rio de Janeiro

Passport: CS 660727, issued on September, 7th. 2006

Home Address: 39, Rue de la Servette, Switzerland, CH-1202

andre.dos.anjos@cern.ch
http://andre.adois.org



SUMMARY

André Anjos started his Electronics Engineering studies in 1994, at the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, specializing in computing and signal processing. There, he publishes his first international paper in January 1997, on neural networks using a parallelized DSP implementation and defends his diploma thesis, only 3 years after starting his studies. Still on that year, he is invited for a 1-year technical scholarship at CERN.

In 2001 he obtains a Master of Science degree, proposing a highly efficient discrimination system based on neural networks for the ATLAS experiment at CERN. He continues his engineering studies at CERN obtaining a Doctor of Science degree in 2006.

André currently lives in Geneva, Switzerland, since 2001, working as a Computer Scientist for the ATLAS experiment at CERN's LHC. He has contributions in several areas of the experiment, with nearly 60 published articles, 20 out of those, in peer-reviewed journals. He is also an IEEE reviewer on applied Computing and Electronics.

His main interests are on pattern recognition in signal processing, large and distributed computing, operating systems and networking. He enjoys working on challenging multi-disciplinary problems.

EDUCATION

• 1989-1993

Technical Course in Electronics at the Federal Center of Technology of Rio de Janeiro - CEFET (from 1989 until 1992). Degree issued on 1993;

1994-1999

Electronics Engineering at the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro. Degree issued on December 1999.

• 2000-2001

Masters on Electronics Engineering (Signal Processing) at the Post Graduate Program of the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro (COPPE/UFRJ). Degree issued on June 2001.

• 2001-2006

PhD on Electronics Engineering (Signal Processing) at the Post Graduate Program of the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro (COPPE/UFRJ).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

• 1995-1997

Two and a half years (from begin of 1995 till middle of 1997) as a junior researcher on Signal Processing associated with the Brazilian National Research Program (CNPq) at the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro. Subjects: Digital filtering applied to particle identification, parallel processing in Transputer-based machines and Neural networks applied to particle identification;

• 1997-1998

One year and one month (September, 1997 till October 1998) as a researcher at http://www.cern.ch (European Center for Particle Physics - Geneva - Switzerland), on Systems Engineering. This work was developed in the context of the ATLAS experiment;

• 1998-1999

One year and two months as a researcher on Signal Processing associated with the Signal Processing Laboratory (LPS) at the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro. Subject: High-performance computing applied to Signal Processing;

• 2000-2001

13 months associated with the Post Graduate Program of the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro (COPPE/UFRJ). Subject: Masters on Signal Processing;

• 2001-2004

3 years associated with the Post Graduate Program of the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro (COPPE/UFRJ):

Apr 2001-Nov 2001 Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, pre-thesis work; **Dec 2001-2004** CERN, Switzerland, Collaborating for the implementation of the ATLAS Trigger Prototype.

• 2004-present

I'm currently working on the development and construction of the final ATLAS Trigger System, as a full-time researcher associated with the University of Wisconsin/Madison/USA.

THESIS COMMITTEES

- L.V. Cascão, "Sistema Neural de Detecção de Placas de Veiculos Automotores em Imagens Digitalizadas", Graduation Thesis, Department of Electronics Engineering, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, 16/December/2008.
- J.M. Faier, "Monitoração da Qualidade de Dados em Séries Temporais", Doctorate Qualification, COPPE/PEE, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, 15/December/2008.

PUBLICATIONS

Please consult the separated publication list document.

COMPUTING

- Proficient in various Operating System types, including but not limited to Linux, Microsoft's Windows and Apple's OSX;
- · Advanced system and network administration skills;
- Concepts of networking (intra/Internet), firewalling, Internet publishing, network protocols, architectures and associated technologies;
- Masters structured (C, Pascal, etc.) and object-oriented programming (C++, Java, etc.), including the use of software development tools (Revision Control, Building Environments, Documentation Tools, High-level Description Tools, Testing Frameworks, etc.);

- Masters techniques on concurrent/parallel programming, as well as the concepts of programming on multi-task Operating Systems;
- Experience on building and integrating large software projects, managing releases and software policies;
- Experience on the use and development of databases;

LANGUAGES

- Portuguese Mater language;
- English Read, write and speak fluently;
- French Read, write and speak well;
- Spanish Basic communication skills, can read well.

OFF-WORK ACTIVITIES

These are activities I like to conduct off work when time allows:

Sports Alpine skiing, Mountain hiking, Biking, Squash, Tennis, Swimming;

Music I enjoy playing music. I practice and play various percussive instruments. I can also play a Brazilian Cavaquinho, which is an harmonic instrument used in Brazil;

Computing Explore new programming techniques and tools.